Guide to the James A. Healy Collection of Irish literature, 1870-1976
Department of Special Collections
- CATALOGUE OF MANUSCRIPT, BOXES 1-16
  - PHOTOGRAPHS AND REPRODUCTIONS FROM SLIGO MUSEUM [arranged by artist., All 6 1/2 x 8 1/2" except where indicated] (Box 15, Folder 251)
    - Jack BY, 5 small portraits in a row., Photograph, 9 x 3" (1)
    - Jack BY, painting of man before a cottage., Photograph (1)
    - Jack BY, painting of two men., Photograph (1)
    - Jack BY, painting of horse by seated girls., Photograph (1)
    - Jack BY, painting of crowd beside stone wall., Photograph (1)
    - Jack BY, painting of man on country road., Photograph
    - Jack BY, painting of man and distant beach., Photograph
    - Jack BY, painting of man raising glass., Photograph (1)
    - Jack BY, painting of man in large coat., Photograph (1)
    - Jack BY, painting of clown., Photograph (1)
    - [Jack BY?], painting of crowd with banners in a city., Photograph (1)
    - JBY, portrait of man, March 1903., Photograph (1)
    - JBY, portrait of Padraic Colm, May 1903., Photograph (1)
    - JBY, [self?] portrait, March 1903., Photograph
    - JBY, selfportrait with white hair and beard., Photograph (1)
    - [JBY?], portrait of Starkey, 5-7-03?, Photograph (1)
    - [JBY?], portrait of Lady Gregory, 6-8-13., Photograph (1)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF CUALA PRESS EMPLOYEES (Box 15, Folder 252)
    - 3 Irish News Agency photographs of Kathleen Ryan[?] and Maire Gill[?]
      - [all printed material]
  - CUALA PRESS AND DUN EMER ANNOUNCEMENTS (Box 16, Folder 256)
    - Announcement for DE for [July 1903], winter 1903, April 1904, Jan. 1905 (1), [1905], August 1906, Oct. 1907, and May 1908., Folded sheets, except for the last two, which are two small folded and stitched sheets
    - Announcements for CP for Nov. 1908, May 1909 (1), June 1909, Jan. 1911, Sept. 1911, and Jan. 1913., Two small folded and stitched sheets
    - Cuala Industries, Ltd. Embroidery., Folded sheet (and a slightly different variant)
    - List of handcolored prints, ND.Handcolored illustrations by ECY., Stitched booklet. (Another copy, uncut and unstitched)
    - Ca. 50 miscellaneous announcements (some duplicates). A few annotations. Most recent are dated July 1976
  - CUALA PRESS BOOKLETS (Box 16, Folder 257)
    - List of Books... Printed in Strabane in the Eighteenth Century, comp. by E. R. McC. Dix. 2nd ed., 1908.ECY's bookplate., 28 pp.
    - List of Books... Printed in Armagh in the Eighteenth Century, comp. by E. R. McC. Dix. 2nd ed., 1910.ECY's bookplate., 28 pp.
    - In Memoriam F.H.H., 4-25-14., Uncut; 24 pp.
    - St. Patrick's Breastplate 1912.Handcolored initials; uncut; ECY's bookplate, 8 pp.
    - LY, printed memorial tribute, Elizabeth Corbet Yeats, 2-1-40.LY's bookplate, and inscribed by her to JAH, Booklet; 4 pp.
  - CUALA PRESS BOOKPLATES (Box 16, Folder 258)
  - CUALA PRESS CALENDAR DESIGNS (Box 16, Folder 259)
    - [MCY], crowned child, [1913]
    - Jack BY, sailor and Father Time, [1913?]
    - Beatrice Campbell, Whose days shall yet be good..., [1921]
  - CUALA PRESS CARDS (Box 16, Folder 260)
    145 cards, nearly all annotated and signed by ECY or GY. Many have captions which were typed at CP laid inside
  - CUALA PRESS CARDS PRINTED FOR LORD ABERDEEN AND L.H. BRINDLEY (Box 16, Folder 261)
    - 6 cards printed for Lord Aberdeen, 1914-15,handcolored; captions typed at CP laid inside
    - 2 cards printed for L.H. Brindley, Christmas 1932 and Christmas 1933;designed by ECY; handcolored; captions typed at CP laid inside
    - 4 booklets printed for L.H. Brindley, Christmases 1936-38.ECY's bookplate in first. Captions typed at CP laid inside
  - CUALA PRESS CARDS PRINTED FOR VARIOUS PATRONS (Box 16, Folder 262)
    - Kathleen Garrett, Silence and night..., Christmas 1930;handcolored initial
    - L.G., Breezes singing... for Miss Garrett, Christmas 1930;handcolored initial by ECY
    - [Kathleen Garrett, mountain landscape, 1931]
    - [Kathleen Garrett, St. Patrick, Christmas 1931]
    - Dorothy Blackham, Barnacullia [for Mr. and Mrs. R.B. Garrett, Christmas 1931]
    - Katharine Tynan, The Dove with handcolored illustration by [Jack B. Yeats], for Mary Hammond, [1917?]
    - Same as above, on smaller card, [for customer during Great War]
    - Beatrice Campbell, girl with garland, for herself, Christmas 1920
    - Katherine Tynan Hinkson, The Little Red Rogue, Christmas card for nieces of Mrs. Nicholas Brady, 1929
    - [Esther Ryan design, Christmas card from Riverside Bindery, [1932]
    - Stephen Gwynn, Mother of my yearning... with illustration by ECY, [designed for Irish Literary Society, 1936]
    - Henry Van Dyke, Be glad of life! with illustration by [Dorothy Blackham], Christmas card from Lucy and Caleb Wallace, 1938
    - WBY, Laugh heart again... with illustration by ECY [for Lady Yarrow, 1938]
    - William H. Channing, To live content... with illustration by AP?, [for a customer], ND
    - A thousand welcomes to the day [perhaps an insert for a Christmas card], ND
  - CUALA PRESS ILLUSTRATED POEMS ON SMALL SHEETS (Box 16, Folder 263)
    - William H. Channing, To live content with illustration by AP?
    - Sir Samuel Ferguson, There is honey... with illustration by ECY
    - W. M. Letts, If I had a little house..., illustrated by ECY
    - M. A. Young, A Blessing, illustrated by?, (1)
    - Elizabeth Shane, O! the hills o'Cloganeely, illustated by ECY
  - OTHER OCCASIONAL PIECES FROM THE CUALA PRESS (Box 16, Folder 264)
    - At Home cards for Miss Cunningham. One each of two different designs by ECY
    - Invitation card for Cuala sale, illustrated by [MCY], 1912
    - O'Callaghan, Michael, memorial tribute to, 1921, 4 pp.
    - Hymns Sung at the Wedding of PMFT [and] FCB, 7-29-26
    - Aileen M. Goodwin, The Cuala Press in Ireland, reprinted by CP from The Birmingham Post, [ca. 1930], 8 pp. Two copies, one w/a by ECY
    - Snow-White and Rose-Red. Privately printed theater program designed by ECY for performance on 4-29-33., One of 144 copies. 2 pp.
    - Menu for dinner in honor of Miss S. H. Purser, 3-31-38,illustrated by Jack BY
  - CUALA PRESS: SMALL PRINTS [large prints are kept with CP books] (Box 16, Folder 265)
    - Jack BY, Wishing you not a penny plain....
    - Jack BY, Christmas print of car and Zeppelin
  - CUALA PRESS: LARGE PRINTS [kept in Price case] (Othertype [no box or folder #])
    - Saint Columba, signed AP
    - A Nursery Song for Christmas Eve by Susan L. Mitchell, illustrated by?
    - Susan L. Mitchell, On a hill in Erin...., illustrated by?, (1)
    - The Young Saint Patrick, illustation by AP
    - Description of the person of our Saviour with handcolored initial
    - Four lines of verse in Gaelic, with handcolored initial [translation pencilled on verso: They will be remembered for ever...
    - Rune of Hospitality, illustrated by [Jack BY?]
    - W. M. Letts, When you are old... with illustration of The Hurley Player by Jack BY
    - Untitled print of horses at a fence by Jack BY
    - Sequel to above, at finishing post
    - Untitled print of a cottage by water, by Jack BY
    - Untitled print of a village street, by Jack BY
  - THE GIFT OF MR. J. RICHARD BLANCHARD:, ONE FOLDER: (Box 16)
  - ELIZABETH C. YEATS to ARTHUR B. SPINGARN
    - ECY (Dm) to Dear Sir [Arthur B. Spingarn], 7-24-13., ALS - 2
    - ECY (Dm) to Dear Sir [Arthur B. Spingarn], 8-22-13., ALS - 2, enc. receipt, 8-23-13, ADS - 1
    - ECY (Dm) to [Arthur B.] Spingarn, 3-18-14., ALS - 2, probably enclosing postscript note, AN - 1
    - ECY (Dm) to Dear Sir [Arthur B. Spingarn], 7-6-21., ALS - 2, enc. 2 receipts, ADSs - 2
    - ECY (Dm) to [Arthur B.] Spingarn, 10-25-21., ALS - 2, enc. receipt, ADS - 1
    - ECY (D) to [Arthur B.] Spingarn, 3-24-24., ANS - 2, enc. receipt, ADS - 1 (Box 16)
      [Blanchard gift]
    - ECY (D) to [Arthur B.] Spingarn, 8-25-24., ANS - 2, enc. receipt, ADAS - 1
    - ECY (D) to [Arthur B.] Spingarn, 8-13-25., ANS - 2, enc. receipts, ADSs - 2
      6 printed CP announcements (one annotated)
  - CUALA PRESS: HEALY EXHIBITION KEEPSAKE, 1976 (Box 16)
    Yeats, Michael B., `Something to Perfection Brought': The Cuala Press, with preface by Oswalda Deva. Booklet, published on the occasion of an exhibition of an Irish literature collection given to Stanford University by James A. Healy, with drawings by Jack B. Yeats. The Associates of the Stanford University Libraries and the Department of Special Collections, Stanford, California, October 1976. 500 copies printed at the Cuala Press, Dublin. Copyright 1976 by Michael B. Yeats and Anne Yeats.
    [later addition]
    Photographs are in last box.
    SECTION II THE HEALY COLLECTION OF IRISH LITERATURE BOOKS
    A NOTE ON PART II
    Part II catalogues both the Dun Emer-Cuala Press books and books from other presses. The listing is a single one, arranged alphabetically by author and, within each author, by title.
    The entries for the Dun-Emer-Cuala Press books are long, as they give all details of autographs, bookplates, material laid in, and -- their outstanding feature -- their inscriptions. These have been transcribed as closely as possible to reflect line endings, misspellings, slips, and deletions. Bibliographically however, the entries are brief, as full information on the books can be found in Liam Miller's The Dun Emer, Later the Cuala Press (Dublin: The Cuala Press. 1973) and Alan Wade's bibliography of W. B. Yeats.
    The principle of selection for inclusion here, from the numerous Irish books from other presses in the Healy Collection, has been each book's rarity, inscriptions, literary interest or, occasionally (as in the Jack Yeats exhibition catalogues), reference value.
- Abbey Plays 1899-1948. With a commentary by B. MacNamara. Dublin: [no publisher, n.d.
- Allinghan, William
  - Sixteen Poems. Selected by William Butler Yeats. Dundrum: Dun Emer Press. 1905., 3312
    Case 16/B/1
    One of 200 copies. Unopened. E. C. Yeats' bookplate laid in.
    Inscription on a front flyleaf:
    To James A Healy
    As a child I lived in Sligo
    Allingham was the poet of
    the neighbouring town of Ballyshannon.
    They have an extract from one of his
    poems carved on the bridge there.
    W B Yeats July 1938
    W.B. Yeats' signature on title page.
    Colophon signed by printer: Elizabeth C. Yeats.
- Bax, Clifford, editor
  - Florence Farr, Bernard Shaw and W.B. Yeats. Dublin: Cuala Press. 1941, 3401
    Case 16/B/2
    No. 382 of 500 copies. Unopened.
- Barry, Francis
  - In Dante's Wood. Dublin: Dolmen. 1969.
    No. 28 of 250 copies. Signed.
- Bodkin, Thomas
  - Twelve Irish Artists. Dublin: Waddington. 1940.
- Bowen, Elizabeth
  - Seven Winters. Dublin: Cuala Press. 1942., 3405
    No. 14 of 450 copies.
- Boyd, Ernest.
  - Ireland's Literary Renaissance. New York: Knopf. 1922., 3521
    Case 16/B/3
    Inscribed by Boyd to James A. Healy.
- Brindley, Louis H.
  - Poems. Dublin: Cuala Press. 1945., 3443
    Case 16/B/[UNK]
    One hundred copies privately printed for the author by Esther Ryan and Maire Gill. This is no. 51.
    Errata slip tipped in at front endpaper.
    Holograph letter to Healy from Brindley, 10/6/45, laid in.
    On flyleaf:
    Inscribed
    for
    James A. Healy
    by
    Louis H. Brindley
  - A Broadside, 3418
    [No. 1] Published monthly by the Dun Emer Press, Dundrum, County Dublin; [Nos. 2 and 3] Published monthly by the Cuala Press, Churchtown, Dundrum, County Dublin; [No. 4 and subsequent numbers] Published monthly by E.C. Yeats at the Cuala Press
    In 3 portfolios: June 1908 - May 1910
    June 1910 - May 1912
    June 1912 - May 1915
  - Broadsides: A Collection of New Irish and English Songs 1937. Dublin: Cuala Press, 1937., 3382
    One of 150 copies.
    Introductory essay autographed by the editors, W.B. Yeats and Dorothy Wellesley.
    Elizabeth C. Yeats' bookplate laid in.
- Buchanan, Robert
  - The Buchanan Ballads. London: Haddon. 1892., 3446
    Inscribed to Charles Cartwright by Buchanan.
    Tipped in: Buchanan (Deal) to Cartwright, 6-18-?. ALS - 3.
    Buchanan (Deal) to Cartwright, 6-20-?. ALS -4.
    Auction notices laid in.
- Byrne, Donn
  - Blind Raftery and His Wife, Hilaria. London: Sampson Low, Marston. 1925.
- Cavanagh, Maeve
  - Sheaves of Revolt. Dublin: City Printing Works. 1914.
- Clarke, Austin
  - The Celtic Twilight and the Nineties. Introduction by Roger McHugh. Dublin: Dolmen. 1969.
- Clarke, Austin
  - The Echo at Coole & Other Poems. Dublin: Dolmen. 1968.
- Clarke, Austin
  - The Impuritans. Dublin: Dolmen. 1973.
    One of 350 copies.
- Clark, Austin
  - Later Poems. Dublin: Dolmen. 1961.
- Clarke, Austin
  - Mnemosyne Lay in Dust. Dublin: Dolmen. 1966.
    One of 1000 copies.
- Clarke, Austin
  - Old-Fashioned Pilgrimage and Other Poems. Dublin: Dolmen. 1967.
- Clarke, Austin
  - Poetry in Ireland. Dublin: Colm o Lochlainn. 1951.
- Clarke, Austin
  - Two Interludes. Adapted from Cervantes. Dublin: Dolmen. 1968.
- [Clarke, Austin]
  - A Tribute to Austin Clarke on His Seventieth Birthday. Edited by John Montague and Liam Miller. Dublin: Dolmen. 1966.
- Colum, Mary
  - From These Roots. New York: Scribner's. 1937.
- Colum, Mary
  - Life and the Dream. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday. 1947.
- Colum, Padraic
  - Castle Conquer. New York: Macmillan. 1923., 3565
- Colum, Padraic
  - Dramatic Legends and Other Poems. New York: Macmillan. 1922.
    Inscribed by Colum to Richard Campbell.
- Colum, Padraic
  - Ella Young: An Appreciation. London: Longmans, Green. 1931.
- Colum, Padraic
  - The Fiddler's House. Dublin: Maunsel. 1907., 3450
    Signed by Colum on half title.
- Colum, Padraic
  - Irish Elegies. Dublin: Dolmen. 1958.
    No. 189 of 240 copies.
- Colum, Padraic
  - The King of Ireland's Son. New York: Macmillan. 1921.
    Signed. Healy's note: New edition. Dudley Digges's copy. His gift
- Colum, Padraic
  - The Land. Dublin: Maunsel. 1905., 3451
    (Vol. III of Abbey Theatre Series.)
- Colum, Padraic
  - My Irish Year. London: Mills & Boon. 1912.
    Inscribed by Colum and Ernest Boyd.
- Colum, Padraic
  - Old Pastures. New York: Macmillan. 1930.
    No. 163 of 200 copies. Signed.
- Colum, Padraic and Edward J. O'Brien, editors
  - Poems of the Irish Revolutionary Brotherhood. Boston, Small, Maynard. 1916.
- Colum, Padraic
  - The Road Round Ireland. New York: Macmillan. 1926., 3597
    Inscribed by Colum to Boyd.
- Colum, Padraic
  - Thomas Muskerry. Dublin: Maunsel. 1910.
    - COPY ONE:
      Oliver St. John Gogarty's copy.
    - COPY TWO:
      Inscribed to Boyd.
- Colum, Padraic
  - Three Men. London: Elkin Mathews & Marrot. 1930.
    No. 114 of 530 copies. Signed.
- Colum, Padraic
  - Three Plays. Boston: Little, Brown. 1916.
    - COPY ONE:, 3611
      Dudley Digges' copy.
    - COPY TWO:
      Inscribed to Marie and Dudley Digges.
- Colum, Padraic
  - Wild Earth. Dublin: Maunsel. 1907.
    - COPY ONE:
      Ernest Boyd's copy.
    - COPY TWO:
      Inscribed in Gaelic by author (?)
    - COPY THREE:
      Photograph pasted on to title page.
    - COPY FOUR:
      Inscribed to Dudley Digges.
    - COPY FIVE:
      Inscribed to Richard Campbell.
- [Colum, Padraic, introduction by]
  - Broad-Sheet Ballads. Dublin and London: Maunsel. [1913?]
- Connolly, James B.
  Case 16/B/4
  64 books, mostly inscribed to James A. Healy
  Canton Captain (3643)
  Coaster Captain (3645)
  Gloucestermen (3656)
  Master Mariner (3669)
  Navy Men (3670)
  Sea-Borne (3684)
- [Davis, Thomas]
  - Thomas Davis: The Thinker and Teacher. Edited by Arthur Griffith. Dublin: Gill. 1918.
    J.B. Connolly's copy.
- Devlin, Denis
  - The Heavenly Foreigner. Dublin: Dolmen. 1967.
    Frontispiece by Anne Yeats.
- Dix, Thomas
  - Some Poetical Pieces. With biographical note by E.R. MaC. Dix. [Dundrum:] Cuala Press. 1910.Privately printed.
    E.C. Yeats' bookplate pasted inside front cover.
- Donaghy, John L.
  - At Dawn Above Aherlow: Poems. Dublin: Cuala Press. 1926., 3431
    One of 100 copies privately printed. Unopened.
- Donaghy, Lyle
  - Into the Light, and Other Poems. Dublin: Cuala Press. 1934., 3437
    One of 200 copies privately printed for the author.
- Dowden, Edward, editor
  - A woman's Reliquary. Dundrum: Cuala Press. 1913.
    - COPY ONE:, 3325
      One of 300 copies. Unopened. E.C. Yeats' bookplate laid in.
      James A Healy from W B Yeats Had nothing to do with this book, a temporary rebellion on the part of my sisters. July 1938.
      Inscribed by printer below colophon:
      Elizabeth C. Yeats ----
      Mrs. Edward Dowden Professor Edward Dowden's second wife, one day brought us the M.S. of this book telling us of course that her husband had found this M.S. & wished us to print & publish it -- I who knew of their romance of course guessed the author of this [?] poems -- but it was not till the book was almost printed I ventured to suggest that Mrs. Dowden (then over 80) Should add the note note the reader will find printed in red facing page 1.
      E.C.Y.
      Mrs. Dowden was daughter of Dean Dickenson - dean of St. Patrick Cathedral -------
    - COPY TWO:, 3326
      Hilda Dowden's copy with her bookplate.
      Inscribed by author on free front endpaper:
      H.M.D. from E.D.D. Nov. 1913
- Dunsany, Edward J.M.D.P.
  - Selections from the Writings of Lord Dunsany. Introduction by William Butler Yeats. Dundrum: Cuala Press. 1912., 3323
    One of 250 copies. Unopened.
    E. C. Yeats' bookplate laid in.
    To James A Healy from W B Yeats This book of a fine writer but a nuisance of a man. July 1938.
    Introduction signed: W B Yeats.
    Colophon signed by printer: Elizabeth C Yeats.
- [Dunsany, Edward J.M.D.P.]
  - Dunsany the Dramatist. By E.H. Bierstadt. Boston: Little, Brown. 1920.
- Eglinton, John
  - Bards and Saints. Dublin: Tower Press. 1906.
- Eglinton, John
  - Confidential, or Take It or Leave It. London: Fortune. 1951.
- Eglinton, John
  - Pebbles from a Brook. Dublin: [no publisher[ 1901.
    John Quinn's bookplate laid in.
- Eglinton, John
  - Some Essays and Passages. Selected by William Butler Yeats. Dundrum: Dun Emer Press. 1905.
    - COPY ONE:
      One of 200 copies. Unopened. E.C. Yeats' bookplate laid in.
      Inscriptions on flyleaf:
      John Eglinton (W. K. Magee) Jan. 26, 1926
      W B Yeats Sept 5, 1933
      To James A. Healy Eglinton was the skeptic of our movement, always for the individual against the race. We lived in our better moments WBY July, 1938.
    - COPY TWO:, 3311
      Inscribed on a front flyleaf:
      Ernest A. Boyd from John Eglinton on the eve of his Hegira 25.ix.13
- Eglinton, John
  - Two Essays on the Remnant. Dublin: Whaley. 1894.
- Eliot, T.S.
  - The Dry Salvages. London: Faber. 1941.First edition.
- Fay, W.G. and Carswell, Catherine
  - The Fays of the Abbey Theatre. New York: Harcourt, Brace. 1935.
- Fenollosa, Ernest
  - Certain Noble Plays of Japan. From the manuscript of Ernest Fenollosa, chosen and finished by Ezra Pound, with an introduction by William Butler Yeats. Dundrum: Cuala Press, 1916., 3337
    No. 302 of 350 copies. Unopened. E.C. Yeats' bookplate laid in.
    Inscription on front flyleaf:
    For James A Healy
    Whenever I put into the Cuala books a book not upon an Irish theme it had some relation to Irish work generally at the Abbey Theatre. When this book was published we were about to set out a series of plays in the Japanese manner though on Irish themes. Ezra Pounds translation is in the style afterwards copied by Waley in his well known translations of the Noh drama of Japan.
    W B Yeats July 1938 W.B. Yeats' signature on title page.
- Flower, Robin
  - Love's bitter-sweet: Translations from the Irish Poets of the Sixteenth and Seventeenth Centuries. Dublin: Cuala Press. 1925., 3356
    One of 500 copies. Unopened. E.C. Yeats' bookplate laid in.
    Author's signature on front flyleaf. Inscription below:
    For James A. Healy
    what is the difference between the style of Frank O Connor & Robin Flower? I do not know. Yet O Connor's Translations are better poetry. Robin Flower is however a great scholar.
    W B Yeats 1938
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - As I was Going Down Sackville Street. London: Rich & Cowan. Signed., 3751
- [Gogarty, Oliver St. John]
  - Blight: The Tragedy of Dublin. By Alpha and Omega. Dublin: Talbot Press. 1917.
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - Elbow room. Dublin: Cuala Press. 1939.
    - COPY ONE:, 3390
      One of 450 copies. Unopened.
      Inscribed by the author on front flyleaf:
      To James A. Healy
      Elbow Room.
      Astronomers describe a place Seen through a crack in the vault of Space So dark so absolute so far No light wave from the oldest star, Nor even the thought of God can reach And, fainting, fall on that far beach; abhorrent and inhuman, this, Chineses call `The Great Abyss'. But I am cheered, for now I know There's somewhere left for a man to go - (Always supposing one would care When dead, for going anywhere.) But what a place to make your goal, And lift your head and rouse your soul! Oh! what a place to speak your mind! Without disquieting mankind! There's where I would find elbow room Alone, beyond the Crack of Doom! Oliver St. J Gogarty
    - COPY TWO:, 3391
      Unopened. E.C. Yeats' bookplate laid in.
      Inscribed on front flyleaf:
      W.B.Y. once wrote of Oliver Gogarty's poetry: `He never stops long at his best, but how beautiful that best is, how noble, how joyous!'
      George Yeats Author's signature on title page.
      Inscribed below colophon:
      For James A. Healy This was the last book printed by Elizabeth Corbet Yeats. She passed to her reward on January 16, 1940.
      George Yeats
    - COPY THREE:, 3392
      Unopened.
      Inscribed by author on front flyleaf:
      To
      James A. Healy from Oliver St. John Gogarty
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - Going Native. New York: Duell, Sloan & Pearce. 1940., 3756
    Inscribed to James A. Healy.
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - Hyperthuliana. Dublin: Gaelic Press. 1916.
    One of 25 copies.
    Signed by Gogarty on flyleaf.
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - I Follow St. Patrick. London: Rich & Cowan. 1938., 3758
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - It Isn't This Time of Year At All! Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday. 1954.
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - James Augustine Joyce. Dallas: The Times Herald. 1949.Signed.
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - Mad Grandeur. Philadelphia: Lippincott. 1941.Signed., 3769
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - An Offering of Swans. Dublin: Cuala Press. 1923.
    - COPY ONE:, 3349
      To James A. Healy the New York Maecenas Oliver St. J. Gogarty:
      Inscription below:
      To my friend James A Healy by W B Yeats. That dip in the Liffey made Gogarty a poet. W B Yeats 1938
      W.B. Yeats' preface signed by him. Correction made in second verse of first poem, Non Dolet, probably in Gogarty's hand: Who would survive them to outlast is changed to Who would outlive them to outlast.
      Colophon inscribed by printer:
      Elizabeth C Yeats printed in Senator Yeats' house in Merrion Square.
    - COPY TWO:, 3350
      James A. Healy Our friends go with us as we go. Oliver St J. Gogarty Jan. 10th 1940.
    - COPY THREE:, 3351
      To James A. Healy from his friend Oliver St. J. Gogarty
      It might be of interest to know that the title of this little volume was given to me by W. B. Yeats who, with President Cosgrave, launched the swans on the river from the Dublin University Rowing Club boathouse at Islandbridge.
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - An offering of Swans and Other Poems. London: Eyre & Spottiswoode. 1924.
    - COPY ONE:
      Inscribed to James A. Healy. On free endpaper autograph poem, The Ship, signed.
    - COPY TWO:
      Inscribed to Padraic Colum.
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John
  - Others to Adorn. London: Rich & Cowan. 1938
    Inscribed to James A. Healy. Laid in: signed photograph of Gogarty et al.
- Gogarty, Oliver St. John